https://metaphysics.com/privacy-center/

Home » Privacy Center
Privacy PolicyCookies PolicyWebsite and Data SecurityWebsite Inquiry PolicySubmitting an Enrollment FormOnline Payments PolicyCatalog Request PolicyNewsletter PolicyYour RightsData Subject Request FormOur Sub-processors
Privacy Policy
General Overview
— For More Information Please Refer to the Menu Sidebar
Introduction
Your data privacy and security are important to us, so we have updated our previous privacy policy to reflect the additions and enhancements. This policy takes effect on May 25, 2018. You will find it easy to understand, as this details the steps we have taken to ensure our compliance with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation GDPR. This new regulation will apply to everyone residing within the European Union.
This privacy policy explains our collection, protection, use, disclosure, and retention of your personal data. It reflects greater transparency, giving you detailed explanations of what personal data we can collect from you, how we collect it, what we do with it, who we share your data with, and your data rights. It will also disclose how we share information with third parties or sub-processors. We have also included links to their privacy policies for your reference and information.
New procedures are in place to give you more choices about how you may share and control the information you entrust us with. The new policy also outlines procedures for asking us to limit, or stop using or erase your data.
We are committed to providing you with an experience on this website that is safe, secure, transparent, and trustworthy. To ensure you make a well-informed decision before enrolling in any of our degree programs or using any of our services or products, we suggest you take the time to read through this policy carefully. You will find detailed information on specific privacy policies on the menu sidebar.
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you use our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a Data Controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.
Who are we?
The University of Metaphysics and the University of Sedona are private, postsecondary, distance-learning theological schools operating under the auspices of the International Metaphysical Ministry (IMM). The IMM is a 501 (c)3 non-profit, tax-exempt organization as designated by the Internal Revenue Service of the United States. The curricula of both Universities are strictly non-secular and theological in nature.
You can contact us by mail at 2675 West State Route 89A, # 465, Sedona, Arizona,
86336, by e-mail nospamuom@metaphysics.com or by telephone in the EU or Outside
the US: 00 1 928 203 0730 or US: 1 928 203 0730 or 888 866 4684.
How we use your information
When you use our website
We protect your personal data using administrative security policies and procedures in combination with physical and technical measures to reduce the unauthorized access, misuse, loss, disclosure, and alteration of your personal data. All personal information you provide to us is stored in password-protected databases on our secure servers behind firewalls. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) to ensure that the transmission of sensitive data for payments and donations is encrypted and appropriately safeguarded. We train our employees on the importance of information security and protecting against the unauthorized disclosure of personal data.
Email transmissions are protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) Encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption, which helps to protect personal information in certain areas of our websites during transport of information across the Internet. This is done behind a Dedicated Firewall Server on a Dedicated DDoS Secure Protection Secure Network managed 24/7, 365 days a year.
Our internal server is protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox and is monitored 24/7 365 days a year by Westernnrg.
Our websites are DMCA Protected.
Our websites are SiteLock Protected.
Our websites are PCI Compliant.
Passwords
Combining software, devices and other methods to protect our network.
For payment card information, we use secured networks, encryption or other protection of cardholder data, physical and technical access controls, monitoring and tests of security systems, combined with other data security practices.
When you submit an inquiry/contact us via our website
When you submit an inquiry/contact us via our website, we ask you for your name, contact telephone number and email address. We also record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the internet.
We use this information to respond to your query, including providing you with any requested information about our program, products and services. We may also email you several times after your inquiry in order to follow up on your interest and ensure that we have answered it to your satisfaction. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in providing accurate information prior to an enrollment or purchasing any of our products.
Your inquiry is stored on our secure internal server, protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. Any inquiries relevant to a student’s record, needing to be printed out, are kept in filing cabinets at our secure administration office location. Should any correspondence need to be kept for an extended period of time, it is archived in a secure storage location.
We will address your inquiry and normally respond to you either via telephone or via email.
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
We keep inquiry emails for as long as it is needed to answer your inquiry, or to provide our services, and this depends on the purposes for which we use it, unless applicable law requires we either dispose of it or keep it longer. We will continue to store your personal information to allow us to maintain contact, answer your inquiries, resolve disputes if necessary, and to comply with legal obligations and/or for other legally permissible purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy Notice.
When you submit an enrollment or registration form
Enrollment can be in one of the following programs:
Bachelor
Masters
Doctoral
Additional Doctorate
Continuing Education
Registration can be in one of the following associations:
Alumni Association
Professional Worldwide Metaphysical Association
American Metaphysical Doctors Association
Graduates in Action
Convention and Formal Cap and Gown Ceremony (held every three years.)
The information we ask for enrollment or registration into one of our degree programs or associations can include the following:
First Name
Middle Name
Last Name
Street Address
City
State/Province
Country
ZIP/Postal Code
Cell phone (Mobile Number)
Phone number
Email
Date of birth
Gender
Degree program preference
Education history
Occupation
References
Any felony convictions
Credentials held with any other religious or metaphysical organization
Religious affiliations
Metaphysical/ Spiritual background and experience
Goal/ Intentions
What led you to the program
Association name
What you plan to do professionally
We record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the internet. We will use your information to process and complete your enrollment or registration. We collect and use your data under the conditions of a “lawful basis” personal data collection, compliant with GDPR. If you have indicated a felony conviction on your enrollment form, we are unable to process your data and your collected personal information will be deleted/destroyed.
Your information is collected by a third-party company 123 Form Builder (see privacy policy) and stored on our secure internal server protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. The physical records of active members are kept in filing cabinets at our secure administration office location. Archived members records are removed and kept in a secure storage location.
We will process your enrollment or registration and normally respond to you either via telephone or via email.
We will not use the information to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
When you purchase a product from our website
When you purchase products from us online, we ask you for your name, address, contact telephone number, email address and credit card information. We also record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet.
We will use your information to verify your credit card details for your purchase, process your order and to send you your products. We will also send you a receipt via email, and we may use your telephone number to contact you regarding your purchase.
We require this information in order to process your payment, deliver your products or services, and fulfill our contract with you.
Your information is stored on our secure internal server protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. Your credit card details are passed to a third-party payment processor which is based in the US and requires effective safeguards for your information. We do not retain your credit card information.
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
We keep your order information in hard-copy format without credit card information archived indefinitely, unless otherwise advised by you in writing. If you’ve set up an account with us, your order information without full credit card information, will remain on our secure server for the ease of ordering in the future.
When you request our catalog
When you request to download a catalog, we record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the internet. We also ask for your name, telephone number, and your email address. If you request a hard copy catalog, we will also ask for your mailing address.
We use this information to email you a link to download the catalog. We may also email or phone you after your download in order to follow up on your interest in our university and services. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing to prospects for our university enrollments, products, and services.
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
We will retain your personal information for as long as it is needed to answer your inquiry, or to provide our services, and this depends on the purposes for which we use it, unless applicable law requires we either dispose of it or keep it longer. We will continue to store your personal information to allow us to maintain contact, answer your inquiries, resolve disputes if necessary, and to comply with legal obligations and/or for other legally permissible purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy Notice.
When you sign up to receive our newsletter
When you sign up to receive our newsletter, we ask for your name and your email address. We also record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet.
We will ask for your consent to use your name and email address to email you our newsletter which contains information about our products and other information that we feel might be of interest to you.
You can withdraw your consent at any time, and we will stop sending you the newsletter.
Your information is collected by a third-party company, 123 Form Builder (see privacy policy) and stored on our secure internal server protected by a Sonic Firewall, which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. Your name and email address are added manually to our third-party newsletter email provider, Constant Contact (see privacy policy). This company has contractually committed to providing appropriate safeguards for your personal data which means it will be protected in line with the legal requirements of the EU.
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
We keep your personal data for as long as we produce and distribute our newsletter. If you wish that we no longer keep your information, please contact us at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com
When you submit a review about us
When you decide to submit a review about us, your details are shared with a third-party reviews system. You have the option to submit a review using the following platforms: Trust Pilot (see privacy policy) , Facebook Reviews (see privacy policy), Google+ (see privacy policy), We do not collect your personal data when you write a review through third-party review services. The platform you choose to submit your review has control of your private data, and GDPR compliance responsibility resides with them.
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
You have the right to withdraw your review at any time. You can do so by contacting the platform you used to publish your review.
Transfer of personal data abroad
If you participate in our degree programs, purchase any of our products, or utilize any of our services from a country outside the United States, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. In these instances, your personal data is handled according to this privacy policy. (For more information.) If you are an EU resident where GDPR applies, information that we collect (including through cookies) will be processed and stored in the United States. The appropriate cross-border transfer method governing personal data included in such transfers is the EU Standard Contractual Clauses agreement pursuant to EC Decision 2010/87/EU.
Your rights as a data subject
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate. If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time.
If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or to fulfil a contract, you can ask us to give you a copy of the information in a machine-readable format so that you can transfer it to another provider.
If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or legitimate interest, you can request that your data be erased.
You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.
For more in-depth information please refer to our sidebar “Your Rights”.
To submit a request regarding your personal data by post or telephone, please use the contact information within this document or submit a Data Subject Request Form.
Data subject request form
Please read the sidebar topic “Your Rights as a Data Subject” for more information before completing this form.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, we would prefer you to contact us directly at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com in the first instance so we can address your complaint. However, you can also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at www.ico.org.uk concerns, or write to them at:
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
SK9 5AF
Age restrictions
You are required to be eighteen years of age to enroll in any of our degree programs. Please contact us. If you know of or have reason to believe anyone under the age of 18 has provided us with any personal data. At this this time, if you are a resident of the EU and are under the age of 16, we require parental consent to collect your personal data if you are purchasing any one of our products.
Third party websites
Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be held responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites, and this privacy policy does not govern such sites. We are also not responsible for the content on third-party sites. Please read the privacy policy of any website you visit.
Your rights as a data subject
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate. If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time.
If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or to fulfil a contract, you can ask us to give you a copy of the information in a machine-readable format so that you can transfer it to another provider.
If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or legitimate interest, you can request that your data be erased.
You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.
For more in-depth information please refer to our sidebar “Your Rights”.
To submit a request regarding your personal data by post or telephone, please use the contact information within this document or submit a Data Subject Request Form.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, we would prefer you to contact us directly at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com in the first instance so we can address your complaint. However, you can also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at www.ico.org.uk/concerns, or write to them at:
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
SK9 5AF
California privacy rights
Under California’s Shine the Light law, Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83, California residents who use our website are permitted to request certain information regarding our disclosure of their personal information to any third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make a request, please send an email to nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com For more information: https://consumercal.org/about-cfc/cfc-education-foundation/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa-3/
Updates to this privacy policy
We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time and as our services and use of personal data evolves. If we want to make use of your personal data in a way that we haven’t previously identified, we will contact you to provide information about this and, if necessary, to ask for your consent.
We will update the version number and date of this document each time it is changed.
If you have any questions or concerns regarding the content of this policy, contact nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
Cookie Policy
What is a cookie?
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser.
We take the safety of your personal data very seriously and we collect the data according to prescribed legal regulations. We do not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.
Why we use cookies and what types of cookies are we using?
We uses cookies to identify which pages are being used and improve our website and make our online services work better for you. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
What information do Cookies collect?
When you access or use our Services, we may automatically collect information about you, including:
Technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform.
Cookies may store your login session and other information to make your navigation of our Services easier.
SiteLock Cookies: We utilize these cookies, as well as java script, to determine if traffic crawling the site is a bot. SiteLock is part of our Website Security Solution.
We use Google Analytics to track how visitors interact with our website, analyze where traffic is generated from and collect information related to general site engagement.
Ecommerce Log Information: We log information about your use of the Services, access times, pages viewed, your IP address, your general location, Name, Emails, Username, Login Password, Address, Phone Number.
Device Information: We collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version.
For further information please contact us or view our Privacy Policy
Cookies List:
Cookie Name
Function
incap_ses, visid_incap,
nlbi, _utmvbZVuykvY
SiteLock Cookies, are a part of your SiteLock TrueShield Firewall. We utilize these cookies, as well as java script, to determine if traffic crawling the site is a bot. SiteLock is part of our Website Security Solution.
PHPSESSID
This is a simple token used by all PHP applications to identify your unique session. The main purpose of the cookie is to maintain the integrity of your session while transacting information with our website (accessing secure areas, forms submissions etc). It does not store any personal data and is deleted when the visitor closes their browser.
_gid, _ga,_gat_gtag
These cookies are used for Google Analytics. They help us distinguish users, create user segments, increment traffic sessions, count the number of visited pages, calculate the average time spent on a page, and other similar metrics that are based on anonymous traffic and IPs.
IDE
These advertising cookies are stored in Google DoubleClick and are used to personalise advertisements shown to users based on previous visits to our website.
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE,
YSC, PREF cookie
An embedded YouTube video collects visitor information and custom preferences.
NID, 1P_JAR
Google uses these cookies, based on recent searches and interactions, to customise ads on Google websites.
woocommerce_cart_hash, woocommerce_items_in_cart,
wp_woocommerce_session
The first two cookies contain information about the cart as a whole and helps WooCommerce know when the cart data changes. The cookie (wp_woocommerce_session_) contains a unique code for each customer so that it knows where to find the cart data in the database for each customer. No personal information is stored within these cookies.
wordpress_sec
wordpress_logged_in
wordpress_test_cookie
WordPress uses cookies, or tiny pieces of information stored on your computer, to verify who you are. There are cookies for logged in users and for commenters.
gwcc
At this time the purpose of this specific cookie is Unclassified on the Internet. Session expiry is 3 months.
Unclassified cookies are cookies that we are in the process of classifying, together with the providers of individual cookies.
intercom-id-l0d8dwxp
Intercom enables us to offer a live chat feature on our website. This cookie attempts to remember a user such that they may continue their conversation between different pages of the site, and resume the conversation on repeat visits to the site.
Website and Data Security
How We Protect Your Personal Data
We protect your personal data using administrative security policies and procedures in combination with physical and technical measures to reduce the unauthorized access, misuse, loss, disclosure, and alteration of your personal data. All personal information you provide to us is stored in password-protected databases on our secure servers behind firewalls. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) to ensure that the transmission of sensitive data for payments and donations is encrypted and appropriately safeguarded. We train our employees on the importance of information security and protecting against the unauthorized disclosure of personal data.
Email transmissions are protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) Encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption, which helps to protect personal information in certain areas of our websites during transport of information across the Internet. This is done behind a Dedicated Firewall Server on a Dedicated DDoS Secure Protection Secure Network managed 24/7, 365 days a year.
Our internal server is protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox and is monitored 24/7 365 days a year by Westernnrg.
Our websites are DMCA Protected.
Our websites are SiteLock Protected.
Our websites are PCI Compliant.
Passwords
Combining software, devices and other methods to protect our network.
For payment card information, we use secured networks, encryption or other protection of cardholder data, physical and technical access controls, monitoring and tests of security systems, combined with other data security practices.
When You Submit an Inquiry via Our Website
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you submit an inquiry to us via our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.
Who are we?
The University of Metaphysics and the University of Sedona are private, postsecondary, distance-learning theological schools operating under the auspices of the International Metaphysical Ministry (IMM). The IMM is a 501 (c)3 non-profit, tax-exempt organization as designated by the Internal Revenue Service of the United States. The curricula of both Universities are strictly non-secular and theological in nature.
You can contact us by mail at 2675 West State Route 89A, # 465, Sedona, Arizona,
86336, by e-mail nospamuom@metaphysics.com or by telephone in the EU or Outside
the US: 00 1 928 203 0730 or US: 1 928 203 0730 or 888 866 4684.
Any inquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
What personal data do we collect?
When you submit an inquiry to us, we ask you for your name, your email address and a brief description of your inquiry.
Why do we collect this information?
We will use your information to respond to your inquiry and to provide you with the information you need so you can make a well-informed decision. We do this in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract i.e. as part of pre-enrollment activity or to address any questions or concerns you many have.
What do we do with your information?
Your inquiry is stored on our secure internal server, protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. Any inquiries relevant to a student’s record, needing to be printed out, are kept in filing cabinets at our secure administration office location. Should any correspondence need to be kept for an extended period of time, it is archived in a secure storage location.
We will address your inquiry and normally respond to you either via telephone or via email.
We will not use the information to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
How long do we keep your information for?
We will retain your personal information for as long as it is needed to answer your inquiry, or to provide our Services, and this depends on the purposes for which we use it, unless applicable law requires we either dispose of it or keep it longer. We will continue to store your personal information to allow us to maintain contact, answer your inquiries, resolve disputes if necessary, and to comply with legal obligations and/or for other legally permissible purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy Notice.
Your rights over your information
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, you can see it, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.
You can also ask for it to be erased and you can ask for us to give you a copy of the information.
You can also ask us to stop using your information at any time, by emailing, writing or telephoning us using the contact details in this Privacy Policy Notice.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, please contact our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com
For European Union Residents Only:
Information Commissioner’s Office via their website www.ico.org.uk concerns or write to them at
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
SK9 5AF
Privacy Notice – Enrollment Form, Association Application,
and Convention – Graduation Registration
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you submit either an enrollment form, association application or convention/graduation registration to us via our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.
Who are we?
The University of Metaphysics and the University of Sedona are private, postsecondary, distance-learning theological schools operating under the auspices of the International Metaphysical Ministry (IMM). The IMM is a 501 (c)3 non-profit, tax-exempt organization as designated by the Internal Revenue Service of the United States. The curricula of both Universities are strictly non-secular and theological in nature.
You can contact us by mail at 2675 West State Route 89A, # 465, Sedona, Arizona,
86336, by e-mail nospamuom@metaphysics.com or by telephone in the EU or Outside
the US: 00 1 928 203 0730 or US: 1 928 203 0730 or 888 866 4684.
Any inquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
What personal data do we collect?
Enrollment can be in one of the following programs:
Bachelor
Doctoral
Additional Doctorate
Continuing Education
Registration can be in one of the following associations:
Alumni Association
Professional Worldwide Metaphysical Association
American Metaphysical Doctors Association
Graduates in Action
Convention and Formal Cap and Gown Ceremony (held every three years.)
The information we ask for enrollment or registration into one of our degree programs or associations can include the following:
First Name
Middle Name
Last Name
Street Address
City
State/Province
Country
Zip/Postal Code
Cell phone (Mobile Number)
Phone number
Email
Date of birth
Gender
Degree program preference
Education history
Occupation
References
Any felony convictions
Credentials held with any other religious or metaphysical organization
Religious affiliations
Metaphysical/ Spiritual background and experience
Goal/ Intentions
What led you to the program
Association name
What you plan to do professionally
Why do we collect this information?
We will use your information to process and complete your enrollment or registration. We collect and use your data under the conditions of a “lawful basis” personal data collection, compliant with GDPR. If you have indicated a felony conviction on your enrollment form, we are unable to process your data and your collected personal information will be deleted/destroyed.
What do we do with your information?
Your information is collected by a third party company 123 Form Builder (see privacy policy) and stored on our secure internal server protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. The physical records of active members are kept in filing cabinets at our secure administration office location. Archived members records are removed and kept in a secure storage location.
We will process your enrollment or registration and normally respond to you either via telephone or via email.
We will not use the information to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
How long do we keep your information for?
Once you become a student, we keep your information indefinitely. We will retain your personal information for as long as it is needed to provide our Services, and this depends on the purposes for which we use it, unless applicable law requires we either dispose of it or keep it longer. We will continue to store your personal information to allow us to maintain your student record, answer your inquiries, resolve disputes if necessary, and to comply with legal obligations and/or for other legally permissible purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy Notice.
Your rights over your information
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, you can see it, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.
You can also ask us to give you a copy of the information and to stop using your information if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.
You can also ask for your record to be archived. Once archived, you will not hear from us again, unless you request that your record be re-instated.
You can also request that your record/information be removed or destroyed by contacting us at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, please contact our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
For European Union Residents Only
Information Commissioner’s Office via their website www.ico.org.uk/concerns or write to them at
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
SK9 5AF
When You Purchase a Product, Make a Payment/Donation or Tithe
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you make a payment or donation, or purchase one or more of our products via our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.
Who are we?
The University of Metaphysics and the University of Sedona are private, postsecondary, distance-learning theological schools operating under the auspices of the International Metaphysical Ministry (IMM). The IMM is a 501 (c)3 non-profit, tax-exempt organization as designated by the Internal Revenue Service of the United States. The curricula of both Universities are strictly non-secular and theological in nature.
You can contact us by mail at 2675 West State Route 89A, # 465, Sedona, Arizona, 86336, by e-mail nospamuom@metaphysics.com or by telephone in the EU or Outside the US: 00 1 928 203 0730 or US: 1 928 203 0730 or 888 866 4684.
Any inquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
What personal data do we collect?
When you purchase products from us online, we ask you for your name, address, contact telephone number, email address and credit card information.
Why do we collect this information?
We will use your information to verify your credit card details for your purchase, process your order and to send you your goods. We will also send you a receipt via email and we may use your telephone number to contact you regarding your delivery.
We require this information in order to process your payment, deliver your goods and fulfil our contract with you.
What do we do with your information?
Your information is collected by a third-party company, either 123 Form Builder (see privacy policy) or Woo Commerce (see privacy policy) and stored on our secure internal server protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox.
Your credit card details are passed to third-party payment processors, Authorize.net (see privacy policy) or PayPal (see privacy policy) which are based in the USA and are certified to the EU-US Privacy Shield (which requires effective safeguards for your information). Unless you create an account with us, we do not retain your credit card information. If you do create an account, only your last four-digit numbers are retained. Your order information may be retained in hard copy format, without credit card information in our filing cabinets at our secure administration office location.
We use the United States Post Office (see privacy policy) to deliver your goods and we share with them your name, address, telephone number and email address in order to complete the delivery.
We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
How long do we keep your information for?
We keep your order information in hard-copy format without credit card information archived indefinitely, unless otherwise advised by you in writing. If you’ve set up an account with us, your order information without full credit card information will remain on our secure server for the ease of ordering in the future.
Your rights over your information
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.
You can also ask us to give you a copy of the information and to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.
You have the right to request that your record/information be archived, removed or destroyed by contacting us at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
To submit a request by email, post or telephone, please use the contact information provided in this Privacy Policy Notice.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, please contact our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
For European Union Residents Only:
Information Commissioner’s Office via their website www.ico.org.uk/concerns or write to them at
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
Catalog Request Policy
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you request a catalog from us via our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.
Who are we?
The University of Metaphysics and the University of Sedona are private, postsecondary, distance-learning theological schools operating under the auspices of the International Metaphysical Ministry (IMM). The IMM is a 501 (c)3 non-profit, tax-exempt organization as designated by the Internal Revenue Service of the United States. The curricula of both Universities are strictly non-secular and theological in nature.
You can contact us by mail at 2675 West State Route 89A, # 465, Sedona, Arizona,
86336, by e-mail nospamuom@metaphysics.com or by telephone in the EU or Outside
the US: 00 1 928 203 0730 or US: 1 928 203 0730 or 888 866 4684.
Any inquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
What personal data do we collect?
When you submit an catalog request to us, we ask you for your name, your email address, your physical address and your phone number. There is a provision for you to add a comment or your physical address if you require a catalog to be mailed to you.
Why do we collect this information?
We will use your information to respond to your request of providing you with our catalog and the information you need so you can make a well-informed decision. We do this in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract i.e. as part of pre-enrollment activity or to address any questions or concerns you many have.
What do we do with your information?
Your inquiry is stored on our secure internal server, protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. Catalog requests are printed out, are kept in filing cabinets at our secure administration office location. If requesting an electronic copy, you will be sent a link from which to download our catalog from Amazon Web Services (see privacy policy).
How long do we keep your information for?
We will keep your form filed in our office for thirty days, at which time it will then be shredded and disposed of. We may contact you via phone or email as a follow up to your catalog request. If you would not like any further communication from us, please respond to our email with the message “Unsubscribe.”
We will not use the information to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
We do not sell, distribute or lease your personal data to third-parties.
Your rights over your information
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, you can see it, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.
You can also ask for it to be erased and you can ask for us to give you a copy of the information.
You can also ask us to stop using your information at any time by emailing, writing or telephoning us, using the contact details in this Privacy Policy Notice.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, please contact our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com
For European Union Residents Only:
Information Commissioner’s Office via their website www.ico.org.uk concerns or write to them at
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
SK9 5AF
Privacy Notice – Weekly Newsletter Signup
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you sign up to receive our regular newsletter via our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data.
Who are we?
The University of Metaphysics and the University of Sedona are private, postsecondary, distance-learning theological schools operating under the auspices of the International Metaphysical Ministry (IMM). The IMM is a 501 (c)3 non-profit, tax-exempt organization as designated by the Internal Revenue Service of the United States. The curricula of both Universities are strictly non-secular and theological in nature.
You can contact us by mail at 2675 West State Route 89A, # 465, Sedona, Arizona,
86336, by e-mail nospamuom@metaphysics.com or by telephone in the EU or Outside
the US: 00 1 928 203 0730 or US: 1 928 203 0730 or 888 866 4684.
Any inquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
What personal data do we collect?
When you subscribe to our newsletter, we ask you for your name and your email address.
Why do we collect this information?
We will use your information to send you our newsletter, which contains news and updates about our universities, inspirational messages from our Founder, links to audio and video of IMM’s intellectual property, information about our products, and often includes special offers. Our newsletter also contains links to social media platforms and by accessing them you agree to their terms and conditions and privacy policy.
We ask for your consent to do this, and we will only send you our newsletter for as long as you continue to consent.
What do we do with your information?
Your information is collected by a third-party company 123 Form Builder (see privacy policy) and stored on our secure internal server protected by a Sonic Firewall which includes the real-time Capture Advanced Threat Protection Cloud Sandbox. Your name and email address are added manually to our 3rd party newsletter email provider, Constant Contact (see privacy policy).
We will not use the information to make any automated decisions that might affect you.
How long do we keep your information for?
Your information is kept for as long as you continue to consent to receive our newsletter.
Your rights over your information
By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate.
You can also ask for it to be erased and you can ask for us to give you a copy of the information.
You can also ask us to stop using your information – the simplest way to do this is to withdraw your consent, which you can do at any time, either by clicking the unsubscribe link at the end of any newsletter, or by emailing, writing or telephoning us using the contact details on this Privacy Policy Notice.
Your right to complain
If you have a complaint about our use of your information, please contact our data protection officer at nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com.
For European Union Residents Only
Information Commissioner’s Office via their website www.ico.org.uk concerns or write to them at
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
United Kingdom
SK9 5AF
Your Rights as a Data Subject
The Data Subject Request Form is intended to be used when a data subject exercises one or more of the rights they are granted under the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
The IMM aims to take a proactive approach that places as much control over personal data in the hands of the data subject as possible, with a minimum amount of intervention or involvement from IMM.
However, in some cases, IMM will need to access the request as to whether a request will be allowed or not; where this is the case, the steps involved in this decision making will be in compliance with GDPR regulations and the lawful reasons for our data retention policies.
• The right to withdraw consent
The data subject has the right to withdraw consent where the basis for processing of their personal data is that of consent (i.e. the processing is not based on a different justification allowed by the GDPR such as contractual or legal obligation).
Before excluding the data subject’s personal data from processing, it must be confirmed that consent is indeed the basis of the processing. If not, then the request may be rejected on the grounds that the processing does not require the data subject’s consent. Otherwise, the request should be allowed.
In many cases, the giving and withdrawal of consent will be available electronically i.e. online, and this procedure will not be required.
Where consent involves a child (defined by the GDPR as age 16+ unless changed by law in individual member states) the giving or withdraw
• The right to be informed
At the point where personal data is collected from the data subject or obtained from another source, there is a requirement to inform the data subject about our use of that data and their rights over it.
• The right of access
A data subject has the right to ask IMM whether we process data about them, to have access to that data and in addition the following information:
1. The purposes of the processing
2. The categories of the personal data concerned
3. The recipients, or categories of recipients, of the data, if any, in particular any third countries or international organizations
4. The length of time that the personal data be stored for (or the criteria used to determine that period)
5. The data subject’s rights to rectification or erasure of their personal data and restriction of, or objection to, its processing
6. The data subject’s right to lodge a complaint with IMM
7. Information about the source of the data, if not directly from the data subject
8. Whether the personal data will be subject to automated processing, including profiling and, if so, the logic and potential consequences involved
9. Where the data are transferred to a third country or international organization, information about the safeguards that apply
• The right to rectification
Where personal data is inaccurate, the data subject has the right to request that it be corrected and incomplete personal data completed based on information they may provide.
Where necessary, IMM will take steps to validate the information provided by the data subject to ensure that it is accurate before amending it.
• The right to erasure
Also known as “the right to be forgotten”, the data subject has the right to require IMM to erase personal data about them without undue delay where one of the following applies:
• The personal data are no longer necessary for the purpose for which they were collected
• The data subject withdraws consent and there is no other legal ground for processing
• The data subject objects to the processing of the personal data
• The personal data have been unlawfully processed
• For compliance reasons, i.e. to meet the legal obligations of IMM
• Where the personal data was relevant to the data subject as a child
Reasonable efforts must be made to ensure erasure where the personal data has been made public.
IMM will need to make a decision on each case of such requests as to whether the request can or should be declined for one of the following reasons:
• Right of freedom of expression and information
• Compliance with a legal obligation
• To protect archiving purposes in the public interest
• The personal data is relevant to a legal claim
• The right to restrict processing
The data subject can exercise the right to a restriction of processing of their personal data in one of the following circumstances:
• Where the data subject contests the accuracy of the data, until we have been able to verify its accuracy
• As an alternative to erasure in the circumstances that the processing is unlawful
• Where the data subject needs the data for legal claims but it is no longer required by us
• Whilst a decision on an objection to processing is pending
Where a restriction of processing is in place, the data may be stored but not processed without the data subject’s consent, unless for legal reasons (in which case the data subject must be informed). Other organizations who may process the data on IMM’s behalf must also be informed of the restriction.
• The right to data portability
The data subject has the right to request that their personal data be provided to them in a “structured, commonly-used and machine-readable format” (GDPR Article 20) and to transfer that data to another party e.g. service provider. This applies to personal data for which processing is based on the data subject’s consent and the processing carried out by automated means.
Where feasible, the data subject can also request that the personal data be transferred directly from our systems to those of another provider.
For services that come under this category, little decision-making is required for each case and it is highly desirable that this process is automated in its execution.
• The right to object
The data subject has the right to object to processing that is based on the following legal justifications:
• For the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in IMM.
• For the purposes of the legitimate interests of the IMM.
Once an objection has been made, IMM must justify the grounds on which the processing is based and suspend processing until this is done. Where the personal data is used for direct marketing IMM has no choice but to no longer process the data.
• Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling
The data subject has the right to not be the subject of automated decision-making where the decision has a significant effect on them and can insist on human intervention where appropriate. The data subject also has the right to express their point of view and contest decisions.
There are exceptions to this right, which are if the decision:
• Is necessary for a contract
• Is authorized by law
• Is based on the data subject’s explicit consent
In assessing these types of request, IMM will decide whether the above exceptions apply in the particular case in question.
If you would like to exercise these right in any capacity listed above, please complete the Data Subject Request Form or email us nospamprivacy@metaphysics.com
Data Subject Request Form
This form should be used to submit a data subject request under the provisions of the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
For more information regarding this form, please visit our Privacy Center and click on the sidebar: “Your Rights.”
Once this form is completed, it will be submitted to our data protection officer.
Click here to complete the form
Our Sub-processors
Third Party Subprocessors
123 Form Builder: Data Intake, USA, https://www.123formbuilder.com
1Shoppingcart: Data Intake, USA, http://www.1shoppingcart.com
Authorize.net: Payment Processing, USA, https://www.authorize.net
AWS Amazon: Data Storage, USA, https://aws.amazon.com
PayPal: Payment Processing, USA, https://www.paypal.com
Woo Commerce: Online Ecommerce Processing, USA, https://woocommerce.com
Constant Contact: Newsletter Email Fulfillment, USA, https://www.constantcontact.com
Trust Pilot: Online Reviews, USA, https://www.trustpilot.com
GoToWebinar: Webinar Platform, USA, https://www.gotomeeting.com/webinar/b
SiteLock: Website Security Services, USA, https://www.sitelock.com
Social Network Platforms
Facebook: Social Network Platform, USA, https://www.facebook.com
Twitter: Social Network Platform, USA, https://twitter.com
Linkedin: Social Network Platform, USA, https://www.linkedin.com
Google+: Social Network Platform, USA, https://myaccount.google.com/intro
YouTube: Video Sharing Platform, USA, https://www.youtube.com
Pinterest: Information Discovery Application, USA, https://www.pinterest.com
linkedin_logoUniversity-of-Metaphysics-Twitter-40×40University-of-Metaphysics-Youtube-40×40
Our PCI Compliant Provider
